

MOHAMMAD ALHAMAMSHEH

Social Media, Marketing & Business Development Manager

PERSONAL DETAILS

Bahrain – East Rifaa – Single – Jordanian Driving License (Jordan, UAE & Bahrain)

CONTACT DETAILS

M +973-36914192

E mohammad hammash90@outlook.com Linkedin Mohammad Alhamamsheh Skype malhamamsheh

PROFILE

High experienced level in CRM, Account Management, Business Development Management dedicated to continuous process improvement in the face of rapidly evolving and changing markets. Extremely results-orientated proactive in addressing and resolving problems. Award winning of best performance in key account management, customer relationship manager, technical service management, sales & marketing deal closing, and business strategic management. Experienced portfolio manager with excellent client and project management skills. Action-orientated with strong ability to communicate effectively with technology, executive, and business audiences.

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

ITIL®, Digital Marketing Strategic Plan, Problem Solving & Decision Making, CCNA, Database Analysis, Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure & Python Basic Programming.

EDUCATION

[Geneva Business School - UAE] - [09/2016 - 08/2018] [MBA - Master in International Management]

- Preliminary Thesis of Master: Defining & Measuring the Quality of Customer Service of Telecom Operators in UAE: Targeting Mobile Number Portability (MNP) Customers Based on Data & Voice Services.
- **Final Thesis of Master:** Impact of Digitalization on Existing & Future Jobs in Government Sector in UAE.

[Al Balqa'a Applied University – Jordan] – [09/2008 – 06/2012] [B.Sc. in Telecommunication Engineer]

• **Bachelor Thesis:** Transmit Antenna Selection for Space – Time Block Coding [STBC].

WORK EXPERIENCE

[AD Solutions - Kingdom of Bahrain] - [11/2018 - Ongoing] [Social Media, Marketing & Business Development Manager]

- Developing an effective & engaging content across multiple social channels.
- Managing social media communities by organizing, scheduling & responding to daily posts across FB, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube, G+, and Snapchat.
- Maintaining the brand reputation and growing following & engagement in all platforms.
- Working closely with graphic design team to create a dynamic asset for posts.
- Specifying an ideal social KPI's with monitoring performance & optimizing a content to distribute it in a real time.
- Examining the data gathered from multiple sources & up-level findings & recommendations to improve.
- Managing & analyzing the social media reports.
- Drive and execute strategy for specified client list to grow Media Solutions business in Kingdom of Bahrain.
- Responsible for providing a proposal for each client & supplier.
- Managing the advertising & marketing strategy to develop client campaigns that meet their needs.
- Own and lead the sales & marketing process to improve existing partnerships (through up selling of product and services and sales optimization) and to build strong long term strategic commercial relationships, formalized in enduring contractual agreements.
- Creating a marketing research about the market-share in Bahrain area.
- Creating a marketing strategy for the advertising & marketing services provided by us.
- Determine the financial budgeting for our marketing strategic plan.
- Determine the expected revenues for each market field.
- Managing & analyzing the sales & marketing revenues.

[Etisalat Telecom Group - UAE] - [06/2015 - 08/2018] [Manager/Client Relationship Management & Key Accounts]

- Built and maintained relationships with business client's segments [B2B, B2C & C2B] and key personnel within customer companies.
- Achieved client relationship targets and KPI's as set by the Head of Sales.
- Managed and monitored a day-to-day operational activity of the clients' demands.

SKILLS

Customer Service & Technical Support Customer Relationship Management International Business Management Customer Experience Management Networking & Telecommunication Global Business Model Handling **Presales & Solution Architect** Microsoft Dynamics (BCRM) **Basic Python Programming Digital Services Integration Quality Management Project Management Cloud Computing Digital Computing Account Management** Data Analyst & Reports Marketing Management Leadership Management Team Work Management Social Media & Advertising Sales & Account Management **Negotiation & Conflict Resolving** Hard - Working & E2E - Support Microsoft Office & Big-Data Analysis.

PROJECTS

- Etisalat: Managed Services
 Projects for RTA, MOE, GHQ, AUH Police, DXB-Police, Sharjah
 Municipality, SMB & Channel
 Partner.
- **Etisalat:** Customer Experience Management.
- Umniah: 3.75G (UMTS EVO)
 Wireless Project.

LANGUAGES

- **Arabic** Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- **English** Full Professional Proficiency

- Updated the clients with his order, emails & other requests.
- Conducted business reviews to ensure clients are satisfied with their products and services.
- Attended meetings with clients to build relationships with existing accounts.
- Alerting the sales team to opportunities for further sales within key clients.
- Letting customers know about other products the company offers, working closely with Engineering, Solution Architecture and Sales Consultants.
- Handled customer complaints and respond to all business operation queries.
- Handled Global Business & VIP Customers.
- Escalating and resolving areas of concern as raised by clients.
- Carrying out client satisfaction surveys and reviews.
- Passing leads to the sales team and following up on progress.
- Liaising with internal departments to ensure client needs are fulfilled effectively.
- Monitored company performance against service level agreements and flagging potential issues.
- Updated the CRM and ensuring sales managers and solution architecture are aware of changes within clients.
- Managed sales campaigns, roadshows, and marketing offers.
- Managed Data & Reports Analysis.

[Etisalat Telecom Group - UAE] - [12/2013 - 05/2015] [Analyst/Service Management & Projects]

- To give a solution design to customer and arranged for a technical discussion with customer to clear any technical issues.
- Escalated the suitable issues to management to deliver the service ASAP.
- Provide a quality managed services (Managed WAN, Managed Internet Leased Line, Managed Xpress Connect, M2M-service, Managed VPLS, IDA & IDA+ (Internet Dedicated Access)) to Customers.
- Working closely with sales & presales to clear pending issues with delivered approximately (200-300) managed service (Routers) per month
- Deal with B2B Enterprise, SMB & Channel Partner segments to deliver continuous achievements in delivery and customer satisfaction.
- Managed Data & Reports Analysis.

[Umniah Telecom Company - Jordan] - [11/2012 - 11/2013] [Analyst/Service Management & Projects]

- Upgrade around 650 Links for 3.75 G Network by PATHLOSS program and calculated the interference between the links.
- Used Pasolink V4, Huawei, ZTE, RTN, XMC2, SDH & Other Radio Models.
- Import a different frequency to de-sign the links, test the links & configuration the VLANs.
- Increase the capacity, outage working in operation centers and maintenance the towers.
- Handled a swapping project between ZTE & Huawei devices.

[Umniah Telecom Company - Jordan] - [02/2012 - 10/2012] [RF & Network Optimization Engineer]

- RF Back Office technical support solution (Customer Support).
- Testing radio network performance by using TESM devices.
- Signal performance controlling.